

Anup Kumar Technical Lead

eranupbaranwal@gmail.com

+91 9620444966

Bangalore

anupbaranwal.lovestoblog.com

linkedin.com/in/anupbaranwal in

github.com/anupbaranwal ()

g.......

A Technical lead with 10+ years of Experience in Analysis, Design and Development of Software Applications Architecture. I have always put my main focus on quality of the application and followed approaches like Hexagonal Architecture, Behavioral driven development (BDD) and TDDs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Specialist Software Engineer

Societe Generale Global Solutions Center 🗷

08/2017 - Present

Bengaluru, India

A french multinational Investment bank and financial services company

Achievements/Tasks

- Migrated Legacy application to Angular 10 and Spring boot application written on Hexagonal Architecture (DDD) along with TDDs.
- Wrote batches and scheduled tasks in spring to automate the monotonous tasks.
- Every development done by me is TDD and BDD driven to make sure the technical and functional quality of application is highest with every commit.
- Created Jenkins pipelines and automated CI/CD processes.
- Wrote Implementation plans for successful delivery of application to production.

Application Developer

JPMorgan Chase & Co. 🗷

07/2016 - 08/2017

Bengaluru, India

An american multinational investment bank and financial services company

- Achievements/Tasks
- Developed microservice architecture based application called Coverage which tracks asset management part of custormers.
- Wrote various PL/SQL queries to perform bulk operations on database.
- The application was developed in AngularJS, Java and Spring boot.

Senior Engineer

Honeywell Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd 🗷

06/2015 - 07/2016

Bengaluru, India

A Global Fortune 100 technology company that helps everything from aircraft, buildings, manufacturing plants, supply chains etc.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Worked on software for a voice solution device written mainly in Python and Java.
- Travelled to USA for a business meeting to give my insight and planning of the new application.
- Developed a UI based application in AngularJS to track the stages involved in inspection of aircraft and warehouse events.

SKILLS

Java Spring boot Angular

Kotlin BDD TDD

Docker & Kubernetes

Clean code craftsmanship Consul

Flutter Hexagonal Architecture

SOLID Yoeman Sonar ELK

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Github Crawler 🗹

An automating tool that gathers information about repositories by crawling an organization's repositories through GitHub API. It will be able to report very useful information in few seconds!

Hexagonal App Generator 🗹

A CLI based tool to generate a hexagonal spring boot application along with TDDs, BDDs and various plugins to enforce code quality.

Trade Experts 🗷

A flutter application to bring various expert traders at one platform and share their expertise for free. Trade experts also allows user to get a special recommendation on positional trades. The application can run on ios and android both.

HONOR AWARDS

Oracle certified Java developer Oracle University

Star of the Quarter Award Societe Generale

Winner of Taxathon

Societe Generale

Six Sigma Green Belt

American Society for Quality (ASQ).

Star performer and Spot awards

Honeywell, JDA, Manhattan Associates

Earned various Spot and Star performer awards.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

JDA Software India Pvt. Ltd 🗹

01/2014 - 05/2015

Bengaluru, India

An american software company, providing supply chain management, manufacturing planning, store operations and collaborative category solutions.

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on developing packing solution written in Java and EXTJs for warehouse management.
- Converted existing java based legacy application to new ExtJS and Java based application.
- Wrote fitness tests using selenium to make sure the code quality improves.
- Technical and functional support to stakeholders.

Software Engineer

Manhattan Associates 🗷

08/2011 - 12/2013

Bengaluru, India

65%

An American software company which is best-in-class global solutions provider for supply chain leaders - organizations.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed packing solutions mainly in Java for customers like COLES, eBay, Pepsi etc.
- Developes labour management solution in java and jsf.
- Wrote a tool in jsp and servlet which tracks the changes done by user in the workflow of warehouse management data.
- Worked on production and go live support for the delivery to COLES Australia

EDUCATION

PG Diploma in Advance Computing (DAC) CDAC, ACTS Pune

01/2011 - 08/2011

Courses

Completed 6 months of diploma course from CDAC, ACTS Pune (A very reputed Indian government organization based known for making first super computer in the country)

Bachelor of Computer application (BCA)

Gwalior Institute of Computer Technology

07/2007 - 12/2010

Courses Completed my graduation in computer application and science from Gwalior Institute of computer technology. (Jiwaji University)

LANGUAGES

English









Hindi







RECOMMENDATIONS

Anand Tripathi 🗹

"Anup is a fantastic person to work with, and is a multi-skilled and insightful colleague. Achievement oriented, responsible and strong and his technical knowledge is deep and thorough. Always maintains very good relation with co-workers and clients and can focus on many tasks at once. He is quick in grasping any new technology and good team player. Great employee with a very strong problem solving skills, I definitely recommend working with him.'

Antara Sinha 🛂

"Anup worked on my team as a software developer. During the one year period, he demonstrated excellent technical and cross-team collaboration skills. He has an extraordinary capability to master new technologies rapidly and produce excellent ontime deliverables. Anup demonstrated complete ownership of several product features design and development and was an invaluable resource.

Pradeep Acharya 🗹

"Anup is very hard working man and a good team player. He is a highly committed individual with a great sense of responsibility. Takes complete ownership of assigned task.

Allaka Viswanath Rao 🗹

"He is a very nice guy. He is very talented, hard working, technically very strong and very committed. He is also a very good team player."

TALKS

Hexagonal Architecture

Presented the talk in Societe Generale with a KATA

Commit and Code Review Guidelines

Presented the talk in Societe Generale with a KATA

Craftmanship

Presented the talk in Societe Generale with a KATA

INTERESTS

Cooking

Teaching

Drawing